Haozhe XU

email: haozhe.xu3@gmail.com website: https://www.haozhexu.me GitHub: http://www.github.com/haozhexu LinkedIn: http://au.linkedin.com/in/haoever

mobile: +61 412 735 999

Professional Statement

I'm a highly skilled Mobile Developer with 8 years of commercial iOS development experience. I possess specialised knowledge of different aspects of iOS development and software development life cycle in general. With the experience being developer as well as tech lead I have come to obtain a unique set of skills including iOS development, agile methodology, team leading, team collaboration and so on.

Education

March 2008 - June 2009

Postgraduate Diploma in Science (Computer Science)

Thesis: Staged Event-Driven Architecture on Mobile Devices (J2ME)

The University of Melbourne, Parkville

March 2005 - December 2007

Bachelor of Computer Science

The University of Melbourne, Parkville

Employment History

July 2011 - Present

Outware Mobile - Senior Software Developer

- Developer of ANZ goMoney App, ANZ App
- · Lead developer for AFL Live Official App, NRL Live Official App, Cricket Live Official App
- Team leading junior developers on iOS development
- Performing regular technical interviews, involved in software architecture design

January 2010 - May 2011 (1.5 years)

Self-Employed iPhone Game Developer

2008-2009 (2 years)

Hobbyist Java Developer (J2SE, J2ME)

- Swing GUI Design
- Products: MTextReader (Editor's Pick Award from Brothersoft), BlueBuddy

Personal Projects

I make apps in spare time as a way to learn and try out new technology.

My apps on AppStore: https://itunes.apple.com/developer/haozhe-xu/id917655099

Social Tagman (iOS) - #Tag manager for social network.

https://itunes.apple.com/app/social-tagman/id1433589047?mt=8

fortune I cowsay (iOS) - Mimic the classic fortune and cowboy program on Unix. https://itunes.apple.com/app/fortune-cowsay/id1016269563?mt=8

Ancient Names (iOS) - Ancient Chinese name generator.

https://itunes.apple.com/app/%E5%8F%A4%E4%BA%BA%E5%90%8D/
id1345012854?mt=8

ImSucker (iOS) - Chinese classic poem generator with AI.
 https://itunes.apple.com/app/wo-shi-sao-ke/id963419023?mt=8

Retro Blocks (iOS) - Retro style block matching game. https://itunes.apple.com/app/id917655100?mt=8

East Solitaire (iOS) - Ancient Chinese pebble game. https://itunes.apple.com/app/east-solitaire/id1244283234

Certificates

Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP) - 2003

Sun Certified Java Developer (SCJD) - 2004

Sun Certified Web Component Developer (SCWCD) - 2004

(certification available upon request)